Let me put it to you this way.
让我这么说好了
After the breakup, and the ensuing fleecing of the dad...
办了离婚 榨了我一笔抚养费之后…
Emily went to live with her mother.
艾米丽和她妈妈住在了一起
You know, you try to stay close, but...
我曾想维持亲密的关系，可...
it gets down to holidays, phone calls, birthday cards..., you know.
渐渐就沦为节日拜访、电话中的寒暄 和贺卡上的祝辞， 你知道的。
Anyway...
总之…
Emily goes to college, joins one of her "Save the Poor People"...
艾米丽后来上了大学 还参加了什么救济穷人的组织…
the animals, whatnot...
还是救济动物 没所谓…
meets a guy, decides she loves him.
她遇见了一个男的 觉得自己爱上了他
Good-looking kid, driven, smart.
这男孩儿长得帅 人聪明 又上进
But there was something about him, so...
但我总觉得他有点问题，所以...
when she said they were engaged I told her I was against it...
当女儿说他们已经订婚了 我就告诉她 我反对此事
but being my daughter, naturally...
但作为我的女儿 她很自然的就…
she went ahead and married him anyway.
按她自己的主见 和那男的结婚了
Needless to say, I wasn't invited to the wedding.
不消说 她没邀请我去参加婚礼
That must have hurt.
那一定很伤你的感情
You think?
你这么想？
First time he hit her, she came to me.
他第一次打她之后 她来找我诉苦
I wanted to bash his brains in.
当时气得我想把那小子的脑袋打碎
She wouldn't let me.
她硬拦着我不让我去
Said she loved him, said it wasn't his fault, he'd had a few drinks...
她说她爱他 说不是他的错 只是喝了酒…
she was the one picked the fight.
还说是她先挑起来的
Next time it happened, she didn't come to me.
第二次发生的时候 她没来找我
The ex told me. Nice to hear her voice again.
是前妻告诉我的 能听见那女人的声音 我很高兴
What did you do?
你做了什么？
What any father would do.
做了每个父亲都会做的事
I took care of it.
我出手解决了
I called a guy who called a guy who handles these kinds of things.
我让我的人又找了个人 专门处理这种事情的人
I don't know what he said, don't know what he did, all I know is he didn't kill him...
我不知道他怎么交代的 也不知道他怎么处理的, 我只知道那男人没死
and my daughter never heard from him again.
但我女儿从此再没听过那男人的消息
How did she react?
她对此事有何反应？
Called me names you wouldn't believe, and worse...
她不仅用最难听的话咒骂我的名字 更没想到的是…
Said I was dead to her.
她还说她的爸爸已经死了
I'm not proud of everything I did...
我做过的事 并不是每件都让我问心无愧
but I'm pretty sure I'd do it all again, so...
但要是再来一次 我肯定还会那么做的, 所以...
if they don't let me into Egyptian heaven because my daughter hates me...
如果因为女儿的恨才不让我上埃及天堂
well, then I guess that's just the way it goes.
那好吧 事情都这样了 我认了
However you answer your two questions.
至少我把两个问题答完了
How do we get down from this tomb?
我们怎么才能下去啊？